malayogamonline.com 2019-05-21

# Malayogamonline.com : malayalee matrimonials

MalayogamOnline.com is a website designed to provide matrimonial services for Malayalees. Visitors may browse the site, search user profiles and other content on our site without entering any personal information. However, we ask for certain personal information, at the time of registration, to create your own matrimonial profile, so that other users on our website may view your profile and establish contact with you, in case they are interested.

Malayogam respects your privacy and recognises the need to protect the personally identifiable information you share with us. We would like to assure you that we follow appropriate standards when it comes to protecting your privacy on our website.

In general, you can visit MalayogamOnline.com without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. We track the Internet address of the domains from which people visit us and analyze this data for trends and statistics, but the individual user remains anonymous.

Some of our web pages use "cookies" so that we can better serve you with customised information when you return to our site. Cookies are identifiers which websites send to the browser on your computer to help identify you during your next visit to the website. You can set your browser to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the option to decide whether or not to accept it. The information we collect and analyze is used to improve our service to you.

We use a secure server for credit card transactions to protect the credit card information of our users 

1\. WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT ?

a) Personal Information: Those personal data which you provide while registering on our platform. It includes name, email id, phone number, educational qualification, occupation, location/city etc.

b) Credentials: The password, OTPs and other security information used for authenticating and accessing the account.

c) Payment Information: If you establish a credit account with us to pay the fees we charge, we collect some additional information, including billing address, credit card number or payment instrument, credit card expiration date and tracking information from checks or money orders.

d) Social Media Data: We let you register with us through social networking platforms such as Google, Facebook, LinkedIn etc. Here, we collect the personal data which you let us access through the APIs.

e) Information automatically collected:

  * Mobile ID - Your mobile device's unique ID number.

  * The Geographic Location of your mobile device.

  * Device Specifications: The technical information about your computer or mobile will be collected (eg: type of device, OS, web browser, IP address etc.) for analysing the trends, managing the site, preventing frauds, tracking the visitor movements, collecting the demographic information etc.

  * Your activity within the service: We monitor and collect the information of your actions such as the users with whom you interact & how you make use of the Service. Collecting this data can help us serve you better by refining our recommendation algorithms, developing new useful features, diagnosing the issues/bugs, and preventing the violation of our Terms of Service.

  * Cookies: We use the cookies - the small bits of data stored on your hard drive, and may let others use it. We use this for monitoring your visits, preferences & settings, authentication purposes, analysing site traffic trends, delivering and studying the effectiveness of advertisements, allowing you to use & control the social features through your browser settings and other tools.

  * Log Files: This includes IP addresses, browser type, ISP referring/exit pages, operating system information etc.

  * Web Beacons: These are small, transparent graphic images (clear gifs or pixel tags) often used along with the cookies for personalizing our services to the users, collecting some information about the visitors. We may use web beacons in email communications too, for studying the customer reactions to the mailers.

2\. HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION ?

  * To facilitate account creation and logon process

  * To facilitate matches

  * To fulfil and manage your subscriptions

  * To post testimonials

  * To deliver targeted advertising to you

  * To administer surveys or reach out to you

  * To request feedback and respond to customer service requests

  * To enforce our terms, conditions and policies

3\. WILL YOUR INFORMATION BE SHARED WITH ANYONE ?

We may share your user data with other users, service providers, partners etc., in the event of a business transaction or for law enforcement purposes, as set out below:

  * Other Users

  * Service Providers

  * Corporate Transactions

  * Required by Law

  * Enforce Legal Rights

  * Third-Party Advertisers

  * Affiliates

  * With your Consent

4\. IS YOUR INFORMATION TRANSFERRED INTERNATIONALLY ?

Your user information may be transferred, stored and processed in regions outside your country. We have our servers located in India. If you are using our Site/App from outside India, please be known that your data may be transferred to, stored and processed by us in our facilities and by those third parties with whom we may share your personal information in India, and in other countries.

If you are a resident in the European Economic Area, then these countries may not have data protection or other laws as comprehensive as those in your country. We will however take all necessary measures to protect your user information in accordance with this privacy policy, terms and conditions.

5\. HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION ?

We keep your user information as long as you use our service or as necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected, to provide the service, resolve disputes, establish legal defenses, conduct audits, pursue legitimate business purposes, enforce our agreements and comply with applicable laws.

6\. HOW DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION SAFE ?

We do our best to protect your information through a system of organizational and technical security measures. We implement such high-level security measures to safeguard your personal information in our hand. Anyway, as we can't guarantee that the internet is always 100% safe, we strongly recommend you to access our service within a secure environment. The transmission of your user information to or from our Site/App is at your own risk.

7\. DO WE COLLECT INFORMATION FROM MINORS ?

We neither collect data from the minors nor try to target them. We do not knowingly gather information from people below 18 years of age or use our data to market them. If you are a parent or legal guardian of a minor and you have found that he/she has provided us his/her information without your knowledge, then you can contact mail@malayogamonline.com. In such cases, we will promptly delete the information from our files.

8\. WHAT ARE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS ?

You can directly proceed to unsubscribe the newsletters which we send. It would take fifteen to thirty business days for the changes to take effect. In case of services pertaining to transactional communication, you may continue to receive emails as a part of our services.

If you are an EU resident, you may have certain rights including:

  * The right not to provide your Personal Information to us

  * The right to access your Personal Information

  * The right to request erasure, or restricting of Processing of your Personal Information

  * The right to have your Personal Information transferred to another controller

  * The right to withdraw your consent

  * The right to lodge complaints with supervisory authorities

Before we can give effect to these rights, we may require proof or need to verify your identity. To request to review, update or delete your personal information, please submit a request by sending an email to [mail@malayogamonline.com.](mailto:mail@malayogamonline.com)

9\. DO WE MAKE UPDATES TO THIS POLICY ?

We may update or change this Privacy Policy from time to time based on the feedback received from our clients or as a result of a change of policy of the organisation.

10\. HOW CAN YOU CONTACT US ABOUT THIS POLICY ?

**Head Office:**

Malayogam Pvt. Ltd,  
31/2165-A3, 1st Floor, White Tower,  
Kuthappadi Road, Thammanam P O,  
Cochin, Kerala, India - 682 032.  
Ph: +91 8592083322, +91 9846303333  
E-mail: mail@malayogamonline.com  
CIN Number : U93090KL2004PTC016804  

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please write in to [mail@malayogamonline.com](mailto:mail@malayogamonline.com)

Effective May 25, 2018 [| Archived versions](https://www.malayogamonline.com/privacy_policy/archive)
